Register of the Leo Eloesser Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1899-1976.
  - "Notes of a Medical Marco Polo: Medical Service to the Chinese People, its Beginnings and its Development,", 1950-1975 (Box 8)
    - Biographical materials. (Folder 8: 1)
      Curricula, program, and notes
  - "Notes of a Medical Marco Polo: Medical Service to the Chinese People, its Beginnings and its Development,", 1950-1975
    - Correspondence (Folder 8: 2)
    - Typescripts
      - First draft (Folder 8: 3)
      - Second draft (Folder 8: 4-5)
      - Third draft (Folder 8: 6-8)
  - "Harold Brunn: 1874-1950,", 1951. (Box-folder 9: 1)
    Correspondence and typescript
  - "Treatment of Insufflated Pulmonary Cavities" (with W. L. Rogers), ca. 1951. (Folder 9: 2)
  - "La labor de la UNICEF más unos apuntes sobre la lucha antituberculosa en los Américas," speech, IX congreso panamericano de la tuberculosis, Quito-Quayaquil, Ecuador, 1951 July 18. (Folder 9: 3)
    Typescripts of Spanish original and English translation
  - "Assembly Line for Country Midwives," The Pacific Spectator, 1953 Spring. (Folder 9: 4)
    Printed copy of English original and typescript of Spanish translation
  - "Apuntes sobre la organización hospitalaria antituberculosa," Revista Mexicana de tuberculosis y aparato repsiratorio, 1954 July-August
    - Printed copy of original publication (Folder 9: 5)
    - Printed copy of version published in Revista Ecuatoriana de enfermedades del torax, 1964 January-April (Folder 9: 6)
  - "A Simplified Obstetrical Phantom," American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 1954 September
    - Illustrations and photographs (Folder 9: 7)
    - Printed copy (Folder 9: 8)
  - Pregnancy, Childbirth and the Newborn, 1955
    - Correspondence (Folder 9: 9)
    - Galley proofs (Folder 9: 10)
    - Printed copy (Folder 9: 11)
    - Reviews (Folder 9: 12)
    - Spanish translation
      - Printed copy of second edition, 1963 (Folder 9: 13)
      - Typescript of revisions for third edition, published in, 1978. (Folder 9: 14)
        Includes related correspondence
  - Resolution, VI congreso nacional de tuberculosis y silicosis, Mexico City, 1955 January 23-29. (Folder 9: 15)
  - Speech, opening session, VI congreso nacional de tuberculosis y silicosis, Mexico City, 1955 January 23-29. (Folder 9: 16)
    Typescript of speech and related correspondence
  - "The Tuberculosis Colony in Baja California and Its Influence in the Programs for the Control of Tuberculosis in North East Mexico," XIII United States-Mexico Border Public Health Association, Mexico City, 1955 May 6-9. (Folder 9: 17)
    Typescript of abstract of speech and accompanying blueprints
  - "A Proposal for Reducing the Cost of Care of the Tuberculous in Countries of Limited Means," The American Review of Tuberculosis and Pulmonary Disease, 1956 March. (Folder 9: 18)
    Correspondence, typescript, and printed copy
  - Editorial, Annals of Surgery, 1963 November. (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - "Night of the Dynamiters," San Francisco Chronicle, 1963 November 2. (Folder 10: 2)
  - "Reminiscences of Erb," The Journal of the American Medical Association, 1964 October 5. (Folder 10: 3)
  - "Some Early American Chest Surgery," Stanford M.D., 1966 October. (Folder 10: 4)
    Correspondence, typescript, illustrations, and printed copy
  - "Tuberculosis in America," lecture, San Francisco Medical History Society, 1969 January 29. (Folder 10: 5)
    Notes, holograph, and typescript
  - "La tuberculosis en las Americas. ¿Importada o doméstica?", XVI congreso latinoamericano de tuberculosis y enfermadades del aparato respiratorio, Mexico City, 1969 April 13-18. (Folder 10: 6)
  - "The City and County Hospital of San Francisco," The American Journal of Surgery, 1969 October. (Folder 10: 7)
  - "Milestones in Chest Surgery," The Journal of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, 1970 August. (Folder 10: 8)
  - "Palabras atrasadas para la formación del medico especialista y reglamentación de las especialidades,", 1970 November 22. (Folder 10: 9)
  - "Fais-ce [sic] que voudras," autobiography, ca. 1973
    - Correspondence (Folder 10: 10)
    - Notes., 1961 (Folder 10: 11)
      Includes Eloessser's draft of his own obituary,
    - Holograph (Folder 10: 12)
    - Typescript fragments (Folder 10: 13)
    - Typescript drafts (Folder 10: 14-15)
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
  - "El pueblo chino y sus servicios medicos,", ca. 1973. (Folder 11: 3)
  - "Under the Spreading Chestnut Tree,", ca. 1973. (Folder 11: 4)
    Holograph, typescript, and three photographs depicting Jesus Servín Prado
  - "Saxton Temple Pope, M.D.," Surgery, 1973 November. (Folder 11: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, The PHAROS, 1976 July. (Folder 11: 6)
- Correspondence, 1904-1971.
  Arranged chronologically
  - 1904 (Folder 11: 7)
  - 1905 (Folder 11: 8-9)
  - 1908 (Folder 11: 10)
  - 1909 (Folder 11: 11)
  - 1940 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
  - 1941 (Folder 12: 3)
  - 1943 (Folder 12: 4)
  - 1945 (Folder 12: 5)
  - 1946 (Folder 12: 6)
  - 1949 (Folder 12: 7)
  - 1952 (Folder 12: 8)
  - 1954 (Folder 12: 9)
  - 1955 (Folder 12: 10)
  - 1956 (Folder 12: 11)
  - 1957 (Folder 12: 12)
  - 1958 (Folder 12: 13)
  - 1959 (Folder 12: 14)
  - 1960 (Folder 12: 15-16)
  - 1961 (Folder 12: 17-18)
  - 1962 (Folder 12: 19)
  - 1963 (Folder 12: 20-21)
  - 1964 (Folder 12: 22)
  - 1966 (Folder 12: 23)
  - 1967 (Folder 12: 24)
  - 1969 (Folder 12: 25)
  - 1970 (Folder 12: 26)
  - 1971 (Folder 12: 27)
- Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy File, 1937-1971. (Box 13)
  Articles; chronology; clippings; correspondence; instructions; map; medical records; military orders and safe conduct passes; and notebook and postcards, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Articles written by Leo Eloesser
    - "A Doctor Writes" in One Year In Spain, 1938. (Folder 13: 1)
    - "A Letter from Spain," This World, 1938 February 13. (Folder 13: 2)
    - "An American Surgeon behind the Battle Lines in Spain," This World, 1938 March 13. (Folder 13: 3)
    - "A Letter from the Edge of Chaos," This World, 1938 May 8. (Folder 13: 4)
    - "Doctors in War," New Masses, 1939 June 20. (Folder 13: 5)
  - Chronology of Eloesser's time in Spain. (Folder 13: 6)
  - Clippings
    - 1938 (Folder 13: 7)
    - 1939 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1937-1938 (Folder 13: 9)
    - Andell, Evelyn, 1938 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Barsky, Edward K., 1938 (Folder 13: 11)
    - Bruzzichesi, Ave, 1938-1940 (Folder 13: 12)
    - Cannon, Walter B., 1944 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Duncan, Cleo, 1938 (Folder 13: 14)
    - Lozada, Manuel, 1938 (Folder 13: 15)
    - Martin, Fredercika, 1970-1971 (Folder 13: 16)
    - Nubiola, Joaquim, 1938-1939 (Folder 13: 17)
    - Recatero, Julio, 1939 (Folder 13: 18)
    - Sargent, Elizabeth, 1971 (Folder 13: 19)
    - Wagnon, Alicia, 1938 (Folder 13: 20)
  - Instructions, 1937 (Folder 13: 21)
  - Map of the Teruel front, 1938. (Folder 13: 22)
  - Medical records, 1938 (Folder 13: 23-24)
  - Military orders and safe conduct passes, 1937-1938 (Folder 13: 25)
  - Notebook, 1937-1938 (Folder 13: 26)
  - Postcards, ca. 1938 (Folder 13: 27)
  - Printed matter, 1937-1939 (Box 14)
    - General
      - Pamphlets
        - 1936-1937 (Folder 14: 1)
        - 1938 (Folder 14: 2)
      - Serial issues, 1939 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Monographs
      - ...and Spain Sings, 1937 (Folder 14: 4)
      - From Spanish Trenches, 1937 (Folder 14: 5)
      - El servicio sanitario del ejército en campaña, 1937 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Programs, 1939 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Speech by Eloesser, undated. (Folder 14: 8)
- UNRRA/UNICEF File, 1945-1952. (Box 15)
  Clippings; correspondence and reports; diary entries; drawings; instructional materials; lectures; manual; maps; statistics and surveys; and translations, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Clippings, 1947-1949 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Correspondence and reports
    - Undated (Folder 15: 2)
    - 1945 (Folder 15: 3)
    - 1946 (Folder 15: 4-5)
    - 1947 (Folder 15: 6)
    - 1948 (Folder 15: 7)
    - 1949 (Folder 15: 8-9)
    - 1950 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Diary entries, undated (Folder 16: 3)
  - Drawings depicting relief activities in China, undated (Folder 16: 4)
  - Instructional materials
    - 1949 (Folder 16: 5)
    - 1950 (Folder 16: 6)
  - Lectures, undated. (Folder 16: 7-8)
    "A Course in Surgery," conducted by Eloesser. Typescript with holograph illustrations
  - Manual, "First Aid," by Eloesser, 1949 January 29. (Folder 16: 9)
  - Maps, undated (Folder 16: 10)
  - Statistics and surveys, 1947-1949 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Translations from Chinese newspapers, 1949-1950. (Folder 16: 12)
    Typescripts
- Joyce Campbell Series, 1948-1994. (Box 17)
  Biographical file; correspondence; speeches and writings; diaries; and notes, arranged by physical form
  - Biographical file, 1950-1982
    - Address books and directory, 1950 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Architectural plans pertaining to an apartment building in San Francisco owned by Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 17: 2)
    - Clippings, 1952 (Folder 17: 3)
    - Conference passes and name tags, 1963-1979 (Folder 17: 4)
    - Curriculum vitae, 1948. (Folder 17: 5)
    - Financial records relating to a clothing export business conducted by Joyce Campbell, 1954 (Folder 17: 6)
    - Health certificate, 1961 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Travel document, 1969 (Folder 17: 8)
    - Program, 1982 (Folder 17: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1994
    - General
      - Christmas cards, 1962-1983 (Folder 17: 10)
      - Letters of condolence concerning the death of Leo Eloesser, 1976-1977 (Folder 17: 11)
    - Unidentified, 1966-1992 (Folder 17: 12)
    - Aboulafia, Bess, 1954 October 2 (Folder 17: 13)
    - Alvarez, Anne, undated (Folder 17: 14)
    - Andrews, Paul, 1973 (Folder 17: 15)
    - Argüeles, Betty, 1983 (Folder 17: 16)
    - Arguero Sanchez, Ruben, 1980 (Folder 17: 17)
    - Armand, Benoit, 1952 (Folder 17: 18)
    - Armand, Lily, 1954 (Folder 17: 19)
    - Arriaga de Miranda, Leticia, 1994-1996 (Folder 17: 20)
    - Barthelemy, Ann, 1999 (Folder 17: 21)
    - Barthelemy, Margaret and Richard, 1985-1988 (Folder 17: 22)
    - Bastida, Remedios, undated (Folder 17: 23)
    - Blades, Brian, 1977 (Folder 17: 24)
    - Bowles, Newton Rowell and Jean, 1968-1996 (Folder 17: 25)
    - Brewer, Lyman A., 1977 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Campbell, A. M., Mr. and Mrs., 1953-1972 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Campbell, Art, 1955-1994 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Campbell, Jay, 1977-1978 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Campbell, Julie, undated (Folder 18: 5)
    - Carr, Robert M., 1988 (Folder 18: 6)
    - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1977 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Cohn, Roy, 1978 (Folder 18: 8)
    - Cole, Martha, undated (Folder 18: 9)
    - Colegio americano de cirujanos (Jorge Ochoa Altamirano, Jorge E. Riggen), 1977 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Conde, Teresa del, 1977 (Folder 18: 11)
    - Cope, Alice, 1969-1978 (Folder 18: 12)
    - Corman, Eli, 1970-1988 (Folder 18: 13)
    - Davies, Ralph, Mrs., undated (Folder 18: 14)
    - Davis, Faurest, 1983-1989 (Folder 18: 15)
    - Ebersprächer, Trude, 1980-1981 (Folder 18: 16)
    - Elkouby, Gilbert, 1953 (Folder 18: 17)
    - Elkus, Elizabeth, 1965-1980 (Folder 18: 18)
    - Eloesser, Leo
      - Undated (Folder 18: 19)
      - 1951 (Folder 18: 20)
      - 1952 (Folder 18: 21)
      - 1953
        - January-August 1953 (Folder 18: 22)
        - September-December 1953 (Folder 18: 23)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - 1955
        - January-June 1955 (Folder 19: 2)
        - July-December 1955 (Folder 19: 3)
      - 1956 (Folder 19: 4)
      - 1957 (Folder 19: 5)
      - 1958 (Folder 19: 6)
      - 1959 (Folder 19: 7)
      - 1960 (Folder 19: 8)
      - 1961 (Folder 19: 9)
      - 1962 (Folder 19: 10)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - 1964 (Folder 20: 2)
      - 1965 (Folder 20: 3)
      - 1966 (Folder 20: 4)
      - 1967 (Folder 20: 5)
      - 1968 (Folder 20: 6)
      - 1969 (Folder 20: 7)
      - 1970 (Folder 20: 8)
      - 1971 (Folder 20: 9)
      - 1972 (Folder 20: 10)
      - 1973 (Folder 20: 11)
      - 1974 (Folder 20: 12)
      - 1976 (Folder 20: 13)
    - Fahlen, Dorothy, undated (Folder 20: 14)
    - Gallegos-Chacon, Alvaro, 1989 (Folder 20: 15)
    - Gonzalez, Dorothy, 1987-1992 (Folder 20: 16)
    - Gunten, Roger von, 1980-1984 (Folder 20: 17)
    - Haber, Paul, 1988 (Folder 20: 18)
    - Hartman, Iris, 1985-1994 (Folder 20: 19)
    - Hatem, George (Ma Haide), 1980-1983 (Folder 20: 20)
    - Herbert, L. M., 1976 (Folder 20: 21)
    - Herrera, Hayden, 1971-1977 (Folder 20: 22)
    - Herzog, Anna, 1970-1977 (Folder 20: 23)
    - Horton, Anne, 1986 (Folder 20: 24)
    - Hunter, David R., 1977-1979 (Folder 20: 25)
    - Instituto indigenista interamericano (Sergio A. Delgado, Gonzalo Rubio Orbe), 1977 (Folder 20: 26)
    - Johnson, Jean, 1988-1993 (Folder 20: 27)
    - LaPlant, Helen, 1958-1977 (Folder 20: 28)
    - Lee, Catherine L., 1998 (Folder 20: 29)
    - Longhborough, Robert, Jr., 1966 (Folder 20: 30)
    - Lurie, Leon M., 1965-1974 (Folder 20: 31)
    - Maino, Jeannette Gould (Folder 20: 32)
    - McNutt, Becky, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Minai, Naila, 1970-1989 (Folder 21: 2)
    - Mitchell, Jackie, 1985 (Folder 21: 3)
    - Montefiore Hospital and Medical Center (Roberto Belmar, Maria E. Diaz), 1979-1982 (Folder 21: 4)
    - Moss, Baron and Joan, undated (Folder 21: 5)
    - Moss, Erna, 1978-1979 (Folder 21: 6)
    - Múgica, Carolina E. de, 1987 (Folder 21: 7)
    - Noyola, Benito, 1957 (Folder 21: 8)
    - Ochsner, Alton, 1977 (Folder 21: 9)
    - Offermann, Fanny, 1976 (Folder 21: 10)
    - Orona-Córdova, Roberta, 1989 (Folder 21: 11)
    - Orrego Puelma, Héctor, 1976 (Folder 21: 12)
    - Pacific Coast Surgical Society (John E. Connolly), 1977 (Folder 21: 13)
    - Perlman, Annette, 1976-1993 (Folder 21: 14)
    - Ponce Villaseñor, Raul, 1977 (Folder 21: 15)
    - Rogers, William Lister (Lefty) and Dorothy, 1976-1993 (Folder 21: 16)
    - Romig, Howard G., 1976 (Folder 21: 17)
    - Santos Rosales, J. Ramiro, 1980 (Folder 21: 18)
    - Scannell, Gordon, 1977-1978 (Folder 21: 19)
    - Selengut, Stanley, 1963 (Folder 21: 20)
    - Shumacker, Harris
      - 1977 (Folder 21: 21)
      - 1978 (Folder 21: 22)
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 21: 23)
      - 1981-1994 (Folder 21: 24)
    - Shumacker, Myrtle, undated (Folder 21: 25)
    - Simpson, Lesley Byrd, 1959 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Slivka, Rose, 1976-1977 (Folder 22: 2)
    - Socorro León, M., 1978-1980 (Folder 22: 3)
    - Stackpole, Peter and Hebe, 1976-1977 (Folder 22: 4)
    - Stackpole, Ralph and Ginette, 1964 (Folder 22: 5)
    - Stackpole-Cuellar, Anne, 1969 (Folder 22: 6)
    - Stark, Rhoda and Bill, 1970-1984 (Folder 22: 7)
    - Stewart, Carolyn, 1994 (Folder 22: 8)
    - Sutch, Bill
      - 1951 (Folder 22: 9)
      - 1952 (Folder 22: 10)
      - 1975 (Folder 22: 11)
    - Szanto, Kit, 1991 (Folder 22: 12)
    - Tejeda, Antonio, 1953-1955 (Folder 22: 13)
    - Varín, Graciela, 1989 (Folder 22: 14)
    - Vasconcelos, Ruben, 1977 (Folder 22: 15)
    - Viel, Benjamin, 1977 (Folder 22: 16)
    - Vincent, Craig, undated (Folder 22: 17)
    - Whiting, Marjorie Grant, 1967-1977 (Folder 22: 18)
    - Wilson, John L., 1988 (Folder 22: 19)
    - Wu, Ying-Kai, 1979 (Folder 22: 20)
    - Yanome, Patricia, 1988 (Folder 22: 21)
    - Zamora, Martha, 1985 (Folder 22: 22)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1953
    - "A Few Days in the Life of Leo Eloesser,", 1953 December. (Folder 22: 23)
      Holograph with watercolor and pencil illustrations by Eloesser
  - Diaries, 1947-1991 (Box 23)
    - 1947 (Folder 23: 1)
    - 1957 (Folder 23: 2)
    - 1959 (Folder 23: 3)
    - 1960 (Folder 23: 4)
    - 1963 (Folder 23: 5)
    - 1973 (Folder 23: 6)
    - 1975-1988 (Folder 23: 7)
    - 1978 (Folder 23: 8-9)
    - 1979 (Folder 23: 10)
    - 1983 (Folder 23: 11)
    - 1984 (Folder 23: 12)
    - 1985-1991 (Folder 23: 13)
  - Notes, 1954-1978 (Box 24)
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 24: 1)
      - 1954-1959 (Folder 24: 2)
      - 1959-1966 (Folder 24: 3)
      - 1963 (Folder 24: 4)
      - ca. 1967 (Folder 24: 5)
      - 1972 (Folder 24: 6)
      - ca. 1975 (Folder 24: 7)
      - 1975-1976 (Folder 24: 8)
    - By subject
      - Agriculture, undated (Folder 24: 9)
      - Architecture, 1980 (Folder 24: 10-11)
      - Art and architecture, undated (Folder 24: 12)
      - China and Spain, ca. 1978 (Folder 24: 13)
      - Medicine and birth control, undated (Folder 24: 14)
      - Music, undated (Box-folder 25: 1)
      - Pre-Columbian civilizations, ca. 1961 (Folder 25: 2)
      - Social and economic conditions, ca. 1975 (Folder 25: 3)
      - Vocabulary, undated (Folder 25: 4)
- Subject File, 1910-1993.
  Brochures, clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Academica Sinica, undated (Folder 25: 5)
  - Addis, Thomas, 1949 (Folder 25: 6)
  - American Committee for Yugoslav Relief, 1945 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Agriculture—United States—California, undated (Folder 25: 8)
  - Argentina—History (1943-1955), 1943-1944 (Folder 25: 9)
  - Barnett, George De Forest, 1955 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Batista, Cicero Romão, 1948 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Beasley, Shadworth O., undated (Folder 25: 12)
  - Bethune, Norman, 1938-1975 (Folder 25: 13-14)
  - Brazil—Social life and customs—20th century, undated (Folder 25: 15)
  - Bridges, Harry, 1940-1955 (Folder 25: 16)
  - Camus, Albert, 1960 (Folder 25: 17)
  - Carrillo Puerto, Felipe, 1954 (Folder 25: 18)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1957-1970 (Folder 25: 19)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, Madame, 1943 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - China—Antiquities, 1984 (Folder 26: 2)
  - China—History (1937-1945), 1940 (Folder 26: 3)
  - China—History—Civil War (1945-1949), 1947 (Folder 26: 4)
  - China—History (1949-1976), 1959-1972 (Folder 26: 5)
  - China—History, (1976-), 1976-1993 (Folder 26: 6)
  - China Lobby, 1952 (Folder 26: 7)
  - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace, 1949 (Folder 26: 8)
  - Czechoslovakia—History (1938-1945), 1939 (Folder 26: 9)
  - Dover, Thomas, 1949 (Folder 26: 10)
  - General Strike, San Francisco, Calif., 1934 (Folder 26: 11-12)
  - Hatem, George, 1973-1978 (Folder 26: 13)
  - Hearn, Lafcardio, 1908 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1937 (Folder 27: 2)
  - Herrera, Rubén, 1961 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1960 (Folder 27: 4)
  - Internal Security—United States—History—20th century
    - 1951 (Folder 27: 5)
    - 1952 (Folder 27: 6-10)
    - 1953 (Folder 27: 11)
  - Kahlo, Frida, 1938-1950. (Folder 27: 12)
    Includes Leo Eloesser's summary of his medical examination of Frida Kahlo, 1950(?) January 26
  - Kappel, Anne Heyneman, 1968 (Folder 27: 13)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1937 (Folder 27: 14)
  - Kinsey, Alfred C., 1953 (Folder 27: 15)
  - Medical care—General, 1973-1983 (Folder 27: 16)
  - Medical care—China
    - 1963-1973 (Folder 27: 17)
    - 1974-1978 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Mexico—Antiquities, 1950 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Mexico—History (1910-1946), 1927-1934 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Mexico—Social life and customs, undated (Folder 28: 4)
  - Modotti, Tina, undated (Folder 28: 5)
  - Mooney, Tom
    - Clippings, 1939-1942 (Folder 28: 6)
    - Leaflets and pamphlet, 1918 (Folder 28: 7)
    - Medical records, 1939-1942. (Folder 28: 8)
      Includes copy of autopsy report by Leo Eloesser
  - Noffziger, Howard C., 1961 (Folder 28: 9)
  - Naval voyages, 1930-1952 (Folder 28: 10)
  - Opera, Chinese, 1947 (Folder 28: 11)
  - Orozco, José Clemente, 1947 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Paleopathology, 1927-1968 (Folder 28: 13)
  - Pate, Maurice, 1965 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Pope, Saxton Temple, 1929-1972 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Refrieger, Anton, 1953 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Rivera, Diego
    - 1929-1950 (Folder 29: 3)
    - 1951-1956 (Folder 29: 4)
    - 1957-1969 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Rugendas, Juan Mauricio, undated (Folder 29: 6)
  - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, 1974 (Folder 29: 7)
  - South West Africa (Namibia), 1948 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Spain—History—Civil War, (1936-1939)
    - 1937-1938 (Folder 29: 9)
    - 1939 (Folder 29: 10)
    - 1940 (Folder 29: 11)
  - Spain—History (1939-1975), 1941-1949 (Folder 29: 12)
  - San Francisco (Calif.)—History—20th century
    - 1922-1936 (Folder 29: 13)
    - 1943-1957 (Folder 29: 14)
  - Stackpole, Ralph, 1932-1973 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Stanley, Leo Leonidas, undated (Folder 30: 2)
  - Tamayo, Rufino, 1953 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Trotsky, Leon, 1940 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Tuberculosis, 1940-1969 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Twain, Mark (Samuel Clemens), 1910 (Folder 30: 6)
  - United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF)
    - 1965-1977 (Folder 30: 7)
    - 1978-1984 (Folder 30: 8)
  - United States—Foreign relations—Taiwan, 1959 (Folder 30: 9)
- Photographs, 1892-1984.; See also Oversize Materials
  Prints and slides, arranged by subject.
  - Eight prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 10)
  - Six prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 11)
  - Eight prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 12)
  - Six prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 13)
  - Thirteen prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 14)
  - Nineteen prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Folder 30: 15)
  - Nineteen prints depicting Leo Eloesser, undated (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser in a hospital ward, San Francisco, undated (Folder 31: 2)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser with his pet dachshund, and one print of dog only, undated (Folder 31: 3)
  - Two prints depicting Leo Eloesser with Isaac Stern and others, undated (Folder 31: 4)
  - Four prints depicting Leo Eloesser sailing on San Francisco Bay, undated (Folder 31: 5)
  - One print of a portrait of Leo Eloesser taken by Brett Weston, undated (Folder 31: 6)
  - One print of a portrait of Leo Eloesser taken by Edward Weston, undated (Folder 31: 7)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Roberto Chacon, undated (Folder 31: 8)
  - Four prints depicting Leo Eloesser in Mexico, undated (Folder 31: 9)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser in Hawaii, undated (Folder 31: 10)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with Joyce Campbell and her mother, undated (Folder 31: 11)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Joyce Campbell, undated (Folder 31: 12)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and Diego Rivera, undated (Folder 31: 13)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser with his brother and sisters, ca. 1892 (Folder 31: 14)
  - Five prints depicting Leo Eloesser and Roberto Chacon, Breslau, Germany, 1904 February 8 (Folder 31: 15)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser using a microscope, ca. 1906 (Folder 31: 16)
  - Thirteen prints depicting Leo Eloesser as a student in Heidelberg, Germany, ca. 1906 (Folder 31: 17)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser performing a medical operation, 1915 October (Folder 31: 18)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser, Lake Leonard, California(?), 1921 (Folder 31: 19)
  - Thirty five prints depicting Leo Eloesser and others on a hunting trip in Northern California, 1923 July (Folder 31: 20)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and others, ca. 1925 (Folder 31: 21)
  - One print depicting Leo Eloesser and other attendees of the meeting of the Pacific Coast Surgical Association, Seattle, Washington, 1931 February 24 (Folder 31: 22)
  - Thirteen prints depicting Leo Eloesser and other members of an amateur chamber music group, San Francisco, 1934 (Folder 31: 23)
  - Four prints depicting Leo Eloesser and other members of a medical relief mission to republican forces during the Spanish Civil War, ca. 1937 (Folder 31: 24)
  - Three prints depicting Leo Eloesser in Spain, ca. 1938 (Folder 31: 25)
  - Thirty one prints depicting Republican casualties and medical relief activities during the Spanish Civil War, ca. 1938. (Folder 31: 26)
    Some prints may depict Leo Eloesser's relief unit, as part of the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy